<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Guides on Appclacks documentation</title>
    <link>https://www.doc.appclacks.com/guides/index.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Guides on Appclacks documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.doc.appclacks.com/guides/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Managing health checks</title>
      <link>https://www.doc.appclacks.com/guides/healthcheck/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.doc.appclacks.com/guides/healthcheck/index.html</guid>
      <description>The Appclacks CLI can be used to manage health checks
How health checks are executed You can choose when you create an health check if it should be executed or not by the Appclacks cloud platform.
It&amp;rsquo;s possible to create health checks on Appclacks but to host yourself the prober executing the health check, or to execute it by both Appclacks and on your infrastructure. See the Appclacks on your private infrastructure guide for more information about self-hosting.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>API tokens management</title>
      <link>https://www.doc.appclacks.com/guides/authentication/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.doc.appclacks.com/guides/authentication/index.html</guid>
      <description>The Getting Started section explains how to install the Appclacks CLI, create an organization and a new token. This guide will go into detail about API token management.
API Tokens permissions You can attach permissions to API tokens to only allow some actions when used. The --permission flag can be used (and repeated) on the appclacks token create command to configure permissions.
The support permissions are:
*: Enable all API calls GetOrganization: Get information about your organization ListAPITokens: List API tokens GetAPIToken: Get information about a specific API token DeleteAPIToken: Delete API tokens GetHealthcheck: Get information about a specific API token CreateHealthcheck: Create health checks DeleteHealthcheck: Delete health checks UpdateHealthcheck: Update health checks ListHealthchecks: List health checks ListHealthchecksResults: List health checks results GetHealthchecksMetrics: Get health checks metrics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Terraform integration</title>
      <link>https://www.doc.appclacks.com/guides/terraform/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.doc.appclacks.com/guides/terraform/index.html</guid>
      <description>You can manage your health checks using the Appclacks Terraform provider. The source code of the provider is available on Github.
Examples are also availabie in the provider Github repository.
Authentication You need to configure authentication against the Appclacks API to make the provider work.
The Appclacks authentication documentation explains how authentication works and how to create an API token. You can either:
Export the APPCLACKS_ORGANIZATION_ID and APPCLACKS_TOKEN values before running Terraform.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes operator</title>
      <link>https://www.doc.appclacks.com/guides/kubernetes/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.doc.appclacks.com/guides/kubernetes/index.html</guid>
      <description>We provide a Kubernetes operator that allows you to configure health checks on Appclacks using Kubernetes Custom Resources Definitions (CRD).
The operator source code is available on Github. CRD examples are available in the config/samples directory.
Getting started You can install the operator on your Kubernetes cluster by following this documentation. We plan to provide an Helm chart in a near future to deploy it.
Creating the required CRDs
All CRD files present in this directory on Github should be applied to your cluster.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metrics and Prometheus integration</title>
      <link>https://www.doc.appclacks.com/guides/metrics/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.doc.appclacks.com/guides/metrics/index.html</guid>
      <description>The Appclacks API exposes health checks metrics in the Prometheus format.
Retrieving the metrics Using the Appclacks CLI
The appclacks healthcheck metrics get command returns all metrics for your health checks in Prometheus format.
Using Prometheus
You can configure Prometheus to scrape the Appclacks API by adding a new job on the scrape_configs section:
scrape_configs: - job_name: &amp;#34;appclacks&amp;#34; metrics_path: &amp;#34;/api/v1/metrics/healthchecks&amp;#34; scheme: https basic_auth: username: &amp;#39;&amp;lt;YOUR ORGANIZATION ID&amp;gt;&amp;#39; password: &amp;#39;&amp;lt;YOUR API TOKEN&amp;gt;&amp;#39; static_configs: - targets: - &amp;#34;api.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Appclacks on your private infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://www.doc.appclacks.com/guides/private-infrastructure/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.doc.appclacks.com/guides/private-infrastructure/index.html</guid>
      <description>Cabourotte, the Appclacks prober, is a free software you can host on your private infrastructure.
It can be retrieved from its Github repository and its documentation is available on https://www.cabourotte.appclacks.com/.
You should configure the discovery section of the Cabourotte configuration file to integrate it with Appclacks. Cabourotte will retrieve the health check configurations from Appclacks and run the health checks.
This is a Cabourotte configuration example:
http: host: &amp;#34;0.0.0.0&amp;#34; port: 9013 discovery: http: - name: &amp;#34;appclacks&amp;#34; interval: 60s host: &amp;#34;api.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Managing your Appclacks account</title>
      <link>https://www.doc.appclacks.com/guides/account/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.doc.appclacks.com/guides/account/index.html</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;ll need to install the Appclacks CLI in order to perform the actions described in this section.
Change your password To change your password, execute the appclacks account password change CLI command.
It will ask you for your account email, current password, and new password.
Reset your password If you forgot your password, you can run appclacks account password send-reset-link --email &amp;lt;your-account-email&amp;gt;. You&amp;rsquo;ll receive a reset link in your email that will redirect you to a page to reset your password.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>